<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mechatronics on Siddharth Kurwa</title>
    <link>/tags/mechatronics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mechatronics on Siddharth Kurwa</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/mechatronics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Cart</title>
      <link>/project/smartcart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/smartcart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: Please review my &lt;a href=&#34;/files/SiddharthKurwa_SmartCartReport.pdf&#34;&gt;final report&lt;/a&gt; and/or &lt;a href=&#34;/files/SiddharthKurwa_SmartCartPoster.pdf&#34;&gt;research poster&lt;/a&gt; for full details of this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Smart Cart was a project I pursued in my senior year to test my capacity and interest for independent research. To start, I prepared and submitted a proposal to the Department of Mechanical Engineering that identified a project advisor - Dr. Carolyn Seepersad, outlined the project scope, and estimated the necessary budget and timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Dr. Seepersad&amp;rsquo;s support after reviewing the proposal, I began pursuing the project to design and prototype a shopping cart that could navigate a grocery store. The stretch goal was for the cart to follow a user around the store, but the minimum technical requirements I imposed on myself for the semester was to design the cart to carry a 25 lbf payload, implement motor control, and develop an obstacle avoidance strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Major tasks involved mechanical design, electrical design, and controls development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially started with the mechanical prototype by analyzing a viable drive system to carry the 25 lbf payload, designing the system using SolidWorks, and prototyping the design. The final design after iterating through SolidWorks is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;CAD.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Mechanical Design&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For electrical design, I decided to use a distributed computing network over the I2C communication protocol. By using a network, I could dedicate individual Arduinos to collecting encoder clicks with interrupts and minimize the risk of missing interrupts as the motor&amp;rsquo;s encoders could click at 3500 Hz at walking speed. Further, the ultrasonic proximity sensors I selected for the obstacle avoidance task required using a delay between the trigger and the echo. This delay would slow down the loop rate of the Arduino (in an undistributed architecture) substantially, causing missed encoder signals and inaccurate wheel velocity measurements for speed control. The distributed network allowed tasks to be managed at asynchronous loop rates and requested on-demand. The planned communication architecture is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;distributedComputing.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Communications Architecture&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The other major task was to develop the control strategy for motor control and obstacle avoidance. I had chosen to use ultrasonic sensors, encoders, and a compass as my sensor inputs. Input from these sensors could be used to manage the decision-making of the system. First, I laid out the architecture in a function block diagram.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;functionDiagram.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Control Strategy&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the PIDs from the block diagram implemented in the Arduino, the next step was to give the controller a way to determine heading and speed setpoints based on environmental factors (obstacle avoidance). To do this, I first simplified the task by assuming that the cart should go forward by default unless an obstacle is detected in its path. Once an obstacle is detected, a decision must be made to pass the obstacle. This strategy is depicted in the following graphic.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;obstacleAvoidance.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Obstacle Avoidance&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;At the conclusion of the semester, this project has given me comprehensive exposure and confidence in independently taking a smart product concept from ideation to prototype - a true testament to my four-year engineering education at the University of Texas at Austin! In particular, this project has inspired me to wopursue a career with early-stage prototyping of smart products and pursue graduate school to enhance my core skills and theoretical knowledge of human-machine interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pitching Machine</title>
      <link>/project/pitchingmachine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/pitchingmachine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an intern at M3 Design, I helped develop a pitching machine for a client. We began with an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.athlonic.com/products/wheelerdealer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;off-the-shelf product&lt;/a&gt; as the foundation and added or modified features until we developed all the functionality required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my co-worker designed and fabricated a 2 degree-of-freedom (DOF) mechanism to enable a controllable pitching window, I focused on developing pitching control. For this, I started by characterizing the existing pitching machine which used a linear solenoid (a device that creates a magnetic field to exert a linear force on a plunger) to pitch the ball.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;linearSolenoid.gif&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Linear Solenoid&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Charcterization involved using an oscilloscope to determining transient operating voltage, peak current, output current decay as battery life wore down, and pulse-width-modulation (PWM) for variable force setting. Upon characterizing, I learned a bit about our electrical/control design - first, the peak amperage draw of the solenoid exceeded 100 amps (albeit for a very short time) and second, it became clear that the SLA battery power supply would be an issue. With continued use, power output from the SLA batteries decayed substantially and deteriorated the pitching window&amp;rsquo;s consistency. Therefore, I decided to try using a battery charging circuit to continually &amp;lsquo;top off&amp;rsquo; the batteries with charge when not in use. However, this was harder than I anticipated. Lead acid batteries (as used in the device), follow a particular charging cycle shown on the below plot.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;SLACharging.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To maximize battery life, we could only perform Stage 2 or Stage 3 charge cycles. However, these stages did not provide sufficient current in the allotted charge time to replenish the charge consumed during discharge time (firing the solenoid). Further, lead-acid batteries do not have long charge/discharge life cylces and begin to degrade within 200-300 discharge cycles according to &lt;a href=&#34;https://batteryuniversity.com/learn/archive/can_the_lead_acid_battery_compete_in_modern_times&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Battery University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I went back to the drawing board and considered an alternative - capacitors. Capacitors, by nature, are designed to handle repeated charge/discharge cycles with minimal wear and are capable of handling more current being pumped in during the charge state than chemical batteries. Due to their charge/discharge robustness], we began exploring using capacitors to provide the instantaneous peak current draw above 100A and sustain the lifespan of the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sizing, ordering, and integrating the capacitors that we&amp;rsquo;d need, it certainly looked ridiculous&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;capBank.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;but it worked! Using MOSFETs to switch on/off capacitor charging and discharging (and frying some in the process) and an Arduino to provide the control signal, we were able to sustain a consistent pitching window and install a successful product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final prototype installed and featured in local news:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/LoG-AqtZELk&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Medical Handpiece Cleaner</title>
      <link>/project/handpiececleaner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/handpiececleaner/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While an intern at M3 Design, I had the unique opportunity of owning the full development of a prototype medical device&amp;rsquo;s control system. The product is intended to clean and lubricate the internals of a client&amp;rsquo;s medical handpieces, improving tool life and sustained quality.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;handpiece.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Medical Handpieces&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To begin, I started by laying out the state machine architecture with a simple breadboarded mock-up using LEDs, switches, pushbuttons, and a display.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;mockUp.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Initial Mock-Up&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the basic states laid out and control developed, I began integrating physical components - motors, pumps, and sensors. With these physical components, processes within each state could be defined, forming a hierarchical state machine and functional physical form.&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;functional.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Functional Prototype&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Physical components also added another layer of complexity with debounce, power supply, overload, and motor control issues. Troubleshooting each one-by-one took time to get right, but it was an excellent way to understand the challenges in transitioning a theoretical idea or mock-up into a physical, useful device. With the physical system, we also worked on tuning the mechanical function of the device. With the mechanical design engineer, I worked to ensure that the pumps were providing the desired fluid pressure head, flowrate, and cycle duration and iteratively tuned the open-loop saturation and gain with sense resistors on the motor driver and control parameters (PWM settings).&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;openLoopControl.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Open-Loop Control&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With the mechanical and control functions solved, user interface and experience took center-stage. Working with the team&amp;rsquo;s industrial designer, we determined workflows the user might follow, edge cases, and information to communicate to the user at each stage (alarm notifications and status/state indicators).&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;userWorkflow.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Sample UI Test Case&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With all the pieces (controls, mechanical, UI) figured out, we finally pieced the prototype together for delivery to the client. This particular project was a great experience in negotiating needs/requirements across a cross-functional team (industrial design, mechanical engineering, and controls engineering). The final prototype was a beautiful &lt;i&gt;and functional&lt;/i&gt; testament to everyone&amp;rsquo;s hard work and collaboration!&lt;/p&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;lookslikeworkslike.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Final Prototype&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CamSketch</title>
      <link>/project/camsketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/camsketch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wikis.utexas.edu/display/RMD/CamSketch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Project Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/skurwa/sketching-mechanism&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page is still in development - please see my &lt;a href=&#34;/files/SiddharthKurwa_Portfolio.pdf&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt; in the meantime. Stay tuned for updates soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeganEgg Scrambler</title>
      <link>/project/veganeggscrambler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/veganeggscrambler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page is still in development - please see my &lt;a href=&#34;/files/SiddharthKurwa_Portfolio.pdf&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt; in the meantime. Stay tuned for updates soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadcopter</title>
      <link>/project/quadcopter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/quadcopter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page is still in development - please see my &lt;a href=&#34;/files/SiddharthKurwa_Portfolio.pdf&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt; in the meantime. Stay tuned for updates soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
